Guide to the Myron Gustin Fincher Papers, 1908-1993
Fincher, Myron Gustin papers, 1908-1993
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Myron Gustin Fincher papers, 1908-1993
24-02-802
Myron G. Fincher
35.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diaries, journals, newsclippings, reports and articles.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal and professional files of the Chair of the Department of Veterinary Medicine and Obstetrics at the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine, including correspondence about students, administrative matters, fertility research, artificial breeding, and the New York State Mastitis Control Program.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Myron G. Fincher was born in Corfu, New York, on November 25, 1898 to Charles Colby Fincher and Cora (Ross) Fincher. He was the youngest of five children. He graduated from high school at the age of sixteen, then worked a number of odd jobs for a year. Then, in 1916, he decided to attend Cornell University's New York State Veterinary College. Upon graduation in 1920, Fincher was offered a position in the College as an instructor in the Department of Medicine and Obstetrics. He earned a Master of Science degree, worked through the ranks, became full professor in 1938, and in 1942 was named Chair of the Department of Veterinary Medicine and Obstetrics and Director of the Ambulatory Clinic, a position he held until his retirement in 1965.
Fincher was also the director of the New York State Mastitis Research and Control program. In 1946, New York State Governor Thomas E. Dewey asked Fincher to create the program, and Cornell was given a large sum of money to implement it. Fincher set up a number of laboratories in order to regulate the mastitis research in the state. The program now operates as Quality Milk Production Services in the College's Diagnostic Laboratory.
Fincher retired from Cornell in 1965, in order to help found a new veterinary college at Ahmadu University in Northern Nigeria, with funding from U.S.A.I.D. (United States Agency for International Development ). From 1965-67, he served there as head of the Department of Surgery and Medicine. When he returned from Nigeria he became a consultant for the Bureau of Veterinary Medicine at the U.S. Food and Drug Administration. He maintained this position until he retired in 1971.
During his career he was widely consulted for his research on the diseases of horses and cattle, specifically in his areas of expertise, infertility and mastitis. He was active in the state, national and international professional organizations, and received many distinguished awards and honors, including the AVMA's Borden Award in 1954, and the New York State Veterinary Medical Association's Veterinarian of the Year in 1963.
Fincher died at the age of 83 on March 2, 1981, in Syracuse, New York. He was survived by his wife, Evelyn (Davis) Fincher and his three daughters, Joyce, Myra and Esther. He is memorialized at the Cornell College of Veterinary Medicine with an annual prize awarded to a fourth-year student who has demonstrated the best work in courses dealing with large-animal obstetrics and reproductive disorders
CHRONOLOGY
1898 Born on November 25, in Corfu, New York
1915 Graduated from Batavia High School
1920 Received his Doctorate in Veterinary Medicine from Cornell University
1924 Married Evelyn Davis (also a Cornell graduate)
1925 Joyce (Fincher) Coye, the Fincher's first daughter, born
1925 Received a Masters in Science from Cornell University
1926 Named assistant professor at Cornell
1926-1927 Spent a sabbatical year at Thoroughbred Horse Farm, Lexington, Kentucky
1927 Esther Margaret (Fincher) Hays born
1938 Named full professor at Cornell
1940 Myra Jean (Fincher) Tennant born
1940 Spent a sabbatical year teaching at Ohio State Veterinary College and Texas A&M
1942 Named Chair of the Department of Medicine and Obstetrics and Director of the Ambulatory Clinic, N.Y.S. Veterinary College
1943-1944 Served as Acting Dean of the N.Y. State Veterinary College while Dean William A. Hagan was in Germany
1944 Elected president of the Alpha Chapter of Phi Zeta, the national veterinary honor society
1946 Named director of the N.Y.S. Mastitis Research and Control Program
1954 Received the Borden Award from the American Veterinary Medical Association
1958-1959 Spent five months as a Fulbright lecturer at the University of Thessaloniki, in Salonica, Greece, where he received an honorary Ph.D.
1960 Traveled to Peru, Uruguay and Brazil as a specialist for the International Education Exchange Service for the U.S. Department of State
1963 Named Veterinarian of the Year by the New York State Veterinary Medical Society
1965 Retired from Cornell University and the Mastitis Research and Control Program
1965-1967 Headed the Department of Surgery and Medicine at Ahmadu Bello University, Northern Nigeria
1967-1971 Consultant for the Bureau of Veterinary Medicine, U.S. Food and Drug Administration
1973 Organized an equine breeding farm in Citanova-March, Italy
1981 Died on March 2, in Syracuse, New York
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Myron G. Fincher papers include biographical material, journals, correspondence, research notes, journal abstracts, articles and photographs, with a focus on his work in veterinary obstetrics, specifically mastitis and infertility. The bulk of the collection consists of general alphabetical files kept during Fincher's tenure at the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine. These files include information about the administration of the college, Fincher's faculty responsibilities, and the New York State Mastitis Control Program. These files also contain material regarding the New York State Veterinary Medical Society and the American Veterinary Medical Association. Frequent correspondents include William A. Hagan, Cassius Way, Walter L. Williams, Walter W. Williams, Arthur Gordon Danks, and New York State Governor Thomas E. Dewey. Additional material in the collection includes personal correspondence, research notes, and professional material relating to his work overseas and with the U.S. Food and Drug Administration's Bureau of Veterinary Medicine. Of particular note is material regarding his work on the U.S.A.I.D. funded project to organize a veterinary college at Ahmadu Bello University in Northern Nigeria.
There is also a series of records in the collection created by Seth Darwin Johnson, who presumably worked with Fincher in the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine's Department of Medicine and Obstetrics.
This collection also contains the records originally accessioned as RMC # 24-01-393.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Fincher, Myron G.; Danks, Arthur Gordon.; Dewey, Thomas E., 1902-1971.; Hagan, William Arthur, 1893-1963.; Way, Cassius.; Williams, Walter Wilkinson, 1892-.; Williams, Walter Long, 1856-1945.; Johnson, Seth Darwin.; Ahmadu Bello University.; American Veterinary Medical Association.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine--Faculty.; New York State Mastitis Control Program.; New York State Veterinary Medical Society.; United States--Agency for International Development.; United States--Bureau of Veterinary Medicine.; United States--Food and Drug Administration.
Subjects:
Mastitis.; Infertility.; Veterinarians.; Veterinary obstetrics.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbook.
RELATED MATERIAL
See also RMC Collection # 13-6-1985, the Artificial Insemination Documentation Project Oral Histories, 1962-1978, which includes references to Myron Fincher. There is also material relating to Fincher in the Collection of Historical Papers and Memorabilia, assembled from the Archives of the Flower and Olin Libraries, compiled by Ellis P. Leonard with the assistance of Susanne Whitaker, located in the Flower-Sprecher Veterinary Library.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
The bulk of the collection consists of Dr. Fincher's Cornell Office Files, which are organized alphabetically by subject and correspondent and broken down chronologically. The rest of the collection is organized by subject.
SERIES LIST
SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL
Boxes 1, 34 and 35
SERIES II. PERSONAL FILES
Boxes 1-2 and 35
The files in this series relate to Fincher's personal and professional life. Of significance are his family letters as well as correspondence with friends and veterinary colleagues such as William Hagan, Cassius Way, A. Gordon Danks and others. The Danks correspondence, in particular, is filled with news from Cornell and provides an intimate glimpse into the lives of its alumni and emeriti.
SERIES III. OVERSEAS WORK
Boxes 2, 33 and 35
Fincher did veterinary work in Greece, Italy, Nigeria and South America. More information about his work overseas can be found in his speeches and articles - see Series VI. Writings and Speeches.
SERIES IV. NEW YORK STATE MASTITIS CONTROL PROGRAM
Box 33
These annual reports were found in Fincher' personal files; Please see Series VIII. Cornell Office Files for more on the New York State Mastitis Control Program.
SERIES V. FOOD AND DRUG ADMINISTRATION FILES
Box 33
These files consist mostly of drug summaries Fincher wrote from 1967-1971 while he was a consultant for the Bureau of Veterinary Medicine at the U.S. Food and Drug Administration.
SERIES VI. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES
Box 33
SERIES VII. VETERINARY EPHEMERA
Boxes 32 and 35
This series consists of catalogs, advertisements, and miscellany collected by Fincher throughout his career. In addition, there is scrapbook of newspaper clippings from 1944-1950. According to a note attached to the book, it was probably compiled by a secretary in the Dean's Office when Fincher was acting Dean. The clippings relate primarily to happenings in the Veterinary College, but some relate to general University news, current events, or medical advances. There is also a list of reprints Fincher kept. These reprints have either been discarded or rehoused in the Veterinary Historical Reprint Collection.
SERIES VIII. CORNELL OFFICE FILES
The files in this series were organized by the creator in a number of alphabetical runs. The files were "broken" on a regular basis. Non-current materials were removed to storage. The archivist has assigned each run a rough date span. However, the date spans are only meant as a guide. Material from years outside of the span may be included. The spans were defined by the archivist, not the creator. The spans should be understood simply as an indicator of when files were pulled to be put in inactive storage.
At the beginning of the series is a run of files created by S.D. Johnson. This is most likely Seth Darwin Johnson, and he presumably worked with Fincher in the Department of Medicine and Obstetrics.
--- S.D. Johnson Files, Box 3
--- 1937, Box 3
--- 1937-1938, Box 3
--- 1942-1943, Boxes 3-4
--- 1944, Boxes 4-5
--- 1945, Box 5
--- 1945-1946, Boxes 5-6
--- 1946-1947, Boxes 6-7
--- 1947-1948, Box 7
--- 1948, Box 8
--- 1948-1949, Boxes 9-10
--- 1949, Boxes 10-11
--- 1949-1950, Boxes 11-12
--- 1950-1951, Boxes 12-13
--- 1951-1952, Boxes 13-14
--- 1952, Boxes 14-16
--- 1953, Boxes 16-17
--- 1954-1955, Boxes 17-19
--- 1954-1955 (2nd run), Box 19
--- 1955-1956, Boxes 19-22
--- 1956-1957, Box 22
--- 1957-1958, Boxes 22-24
--- 1958-1959, Boxes 24-25
--- 1959-1960, Boxes 25-27
--- 1960-1961, Boxes 27-29
--- 1961-1962, Boxes 29-31
--- 1962-1963, Boxes 31-32
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical Material
  - Autobiographical material, ca. 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1928-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings, 1954-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum vitae and lists of publications, 1956-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Certificates, 1921-1972, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Evelyn Davis Fincher and Myron Fincher's Birth Certificates (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - New York State Veterinary College, college notes, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Automobiles, 1922-1955, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Politics, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Material Collected by Evelyn Fincher for Myron's 80th Birthday Party in 1981, 1920-1980 (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - Myron Fincher's Memorial Service, 1981-03-15; CD-3326 (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - "The Family Album of Myron and Evelyn Fincher," compiled by Myra Fincher Tennant, 1993 (Box 34)
  - Myron Fincher's Batavia High School Diploma, 1915-06 (Folder 1)
  - Myron Fincher's License to Practice Veterinary Medicine, 1920-07 (Folder 1)
  - Myron Fincher's Certificate from the Southern Tier Veterinary Medical Association, 1921-07 (Folder 1)
  - Myron Fincher's Membership Certificate from the Society of the Sigma Xi, 1922-05 (Folder 1)
  - Myron Fincher's Membership Certificate of Gamma Alpha Association, 1923-03 (Folder 1)
  - Three Certificates in Greek given to Myron Fincher (Folder 1)
  - Myron Fincher's Doctor of Veterinary Medicine Diploma from Cornell, 1920 (Folder 1)
  - Myron Fincher's Master of Science Diploma from Cornell, 1925 (Folder 1)
  - Evelyn Davis' Bachelor of Arts Diploma from Cornell, 1922 (Folder 1)
  - Esther Margaret Fincher's Bachelor of Arts diploma, 1948-09-21 (Folder 1)
  - Pocket Diaries/Journals
    - Pocket diaries, 1926, 1940, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Pocket diaries from Greece, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Pocket diaries from Greece, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Pocket diaries, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Pocket diaries from Nigeria, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Pocket diaries, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Finances
    - General, 1918-1969, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Housing, 1924-1950, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Income Tax, 1921-1944 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Cornell Appointment Letters and Service Records, 1922-1951 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Stock Certificates, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous Income, 1931-1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Finances kept by Myra Fincher, 1965-1967 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Financial Ledgers including one for payments to Nigerian House Boy, 1933-1967 (Box 35)
  - Ephemera
    - Cornell, 1919-1923, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Alpha Psi, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Omega Tau Sigma, 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Phi Kappa Phi, 1920-1923 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Professional Organizations, 1921-1925, 1956, 1967, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Christmas Cards, ca. 1920-1960 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous, 1920-1944, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Phi Kappa Phi certificate, 1922 (Folder 1)
    - Massachusetts Board Certification, 1920 (Folder 1)
    - Bovine TB article from Dairymen's League News, April 21, 1959 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Commencement Program, 1920 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Reunion Material - Includes Photographs of Classmates, Campus, and Reunions for Classes 1920 and 1922, 1920-1970 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - List of Fulbright Scholars, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - American Agricultural and Technical School in Greece, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Passports, 1958-1973 (Box 35)
    - Scrapbook kept by Joyce Fincher, 1947-1949 (Box 36)
  - Photographs
    - Photographs - Various Family Members, Friends, Trips, Animals, King Ranch and Early Veterinary Professors (1916-1920), 1916-1979 (Box 34)
    - Photograph Album of Horse Farm in Kentucky, 1926-1927 (Box 36)
    - Photographs of friends and family, Undated (Box 36)
- Series II. Personal Files
  - Family Correspondence
    - M.G. Fincher, 1908, 1954, 1970, 1977, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Mother, 1921-1924 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Daughters, 1943-1956, 1974, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous, 1922-1955, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - University of Rochester - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Vet Circle at Cornell - written by Evelyn Fincher, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, ca 1920-1955
    - A, ca. 1920-1955 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - B, ca. 1920-1955 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Baptist Church, 1922-1956, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - C, ca. 1920-1955 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Cold Spring Farm, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - China, 1922-1925, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Cornell University, 1920-1956, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - D-E, ca. 1920-1955 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - F-K, ca. 1920-1955 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Fitch, C.P., 1923-1925, 1929, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Hagan, William A., 1937-1949, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Himyar Stud, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Holstein Friesian Cows, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Hopper, Earle B., 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - International Veterinary Congress, 1934, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Ithaca Board of Education, 1932, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Ithaca Cerebral Palsy Association, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - L-N, ca. 1920-1955 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Moore, Veranus A., 1915, 1924-1928 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - New York State Department of Agriculture and Markets - Bureau of Animal Industry, 1920-1931, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - New York State Department of Civil Service, 1933, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - O-Q, ca. 1920-1955 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Ohio State Veterinary College, 1935, 1940, 1945, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - R, ca. 1920-1955 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Riegeldale Farms [Tryon, Georgia], 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - S, ca. 1920-1955 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - T-V, ca. 1920-1955 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Texas A&M, 1927, 1940, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Tompkins County Farm and Home Bureau, 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - United States Civil Service, 1920-1925 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Vassar Formula, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - W, ca. 1920-1955 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Way, Cassius, 1920-1930, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Westbrook Farm, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Williams, Walter L., 1925-1930, 1940, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Williams, Walter W., 1925-1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 1920-1955 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Various Correspondents, Receipts, Enlistment Records, 1915-1924 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Various Correspondents, 1915-1924 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Various Correspondents, 1924-1964 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, ca 1955-1978
    - ALCOA/Fluorosis, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - ALCOA/Fluorosis - Notebook, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - AVMA, 1958-1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Baker, Donald W., 1965-1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bartlett, David, 1966-1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Benesch, Frans, 1966-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Benson, Jane, 1968, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Colorado State University, 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Cornell University
      - - General Correspondence, 1964-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - - Cornell Veterinarian, 1968, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - - Alumni Association and Reunions, 1969-1978, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - - Class of 1920 Reunions, 1970, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - - Alumni and Faculty clippings and updates, ca. 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - - Miscellaneous, 1969-1976, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Danelius, Gustav, 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Danks, Gordon A., 1967-1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Dean, Paul and Kay, 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Dewey, Thomas E., 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Fox, Francis, 1968-1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Gibbons, Walter, 1972, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Guthrie, Richard S., 1968-1979 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - New York State Veterinary Medical Society, 1963-1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Gutierrez, Joe, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Harrison, Edwin S., 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Hodges, Harry, 1969-1976 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Johnson, Seth, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Nevitt, John, 1974-1975, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Poppensiek, George, 1959-1974 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Kumar, Ashwani, 1966-1978 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Roberts, Steven J., 191968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Sager, Floyd C., 1968-1977 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Sanford, Thomas T., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - U.S. Food and Drug Administration, 1967-1972, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - University of Georgia, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - World Veterinary Congress, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1958-1971 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneous Professional Organizations, 1958-1978 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Programs, 1953-1985 (Box 35, Folder 20)
- Series III. Overseas Work
  - Italy
    - General Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Logistics and Notes, ca. 1973 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence from Myron and Evelyn Fincher from Italy, 1973 (Box 35)
  - Nigeria
    - General Information and Orientation, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - General Correspondence, 1963-1972 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence Home, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Final Report, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Logistics and Finances, 1964-1968, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Lectures and Exams, ca. 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Notes and Case Reports, ca. 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1967-1978 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Miscellaneous, 1966-1970, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Letters from Myron and Evelyn Fincher to Donald and Joyce Coye in Jamesville, New York, 1965-01-1967-06-21 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Letters from Myron and Evelyn Fincher to Myra Fincher from Zaria Nigeria, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Letters from Myron and Evelyn Fincher to Myra Fincher from Zaria Nigeria, 1965 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Letters from Myron and Evelyn Fincher to Myra Fincher from Zaria Nigeria, 1965 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Letters from Myron and Evelyn Fincher to Myra Fincher from Zaria Nigeria, 1965-1967 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Letters from Myron and Evelyn Fincher to Myra Fincher from Zaria Nigeria, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Letters from Myron and Evelyn Fincher to Myra Fincher from Zaria Nigeria, 1965-1967 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Photographs, Programs from Nigeria, 1960-1969 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Photographs - Nigeria, 1960-1969 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Newsletter, 1960-1969 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Newsletter, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Greece
    - General Correspondence, 1957-1959, 1968-1971 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence Home, 1958-1959 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Logistics and Finances, 1958-1959 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - South America, 1960, 1967,1968 (Box 33, Folder 4)
- Series IV: New York State Mastitis Control Program
  - Annual Report, 1947-1948 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report, 1948-1949 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Annual Report - Rough Draft # 1, 1948-1949 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report - Rough Draft # 2, 1948-1949 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Annual Report, 1951-1952 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Annual Report, 1952-1953 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Annual Reports, 1953-1954 - 1955-1956 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Annual Reports, 1959, 1967, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 12)
- Series V: Food and Drug Administration Files
  - "Drugs Studied for Indexing", ca. 1968 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - New Drug Applications Abstracts, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Comparative Clinical Pathology Seminar, Armed Forces Institute of Pathology, August 1969 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Gallimycin-36, ca. 1968 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Iron Dextrin Complex, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Mastitis
    - - Guidelines for Intramammary Infusion Products, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - - Dry Cow Treatments, ca. 1969 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - - Mastitis Products/Robert Baldwin, 1968-1970 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - - Miscellaneous, 21 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Parvex Plus, 1969-1970 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Penicillin, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Sodium selenite and d-Alpha-Tocopherol Acetate, ca. 1968 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Staphylococci, ca. 1968 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Sodium Sulfaethoxypyridazine [ S.E.Z.], 1968 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Sulfamethazine spanbolets, ca. 1965-1968 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Tylosine, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 28)